<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Romain Pellerin's Blog - About me</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/feeds/categories/about-me/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//romainpellerin.eu/</id><updated>2024-08-14T12:14:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Ziele für 2024</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/ziele-fuer-2024.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-18T15:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-02-18T15:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2024-02-18:/ziele-fuer-2024.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dieses Jahr ist mein Jahr&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hier ist er! Mein ester Artikel auf Deutsch. Für ein sehr besonderes Jahr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In die letzte Jahre habe ich mich auf Renrad fahren konzentriert. Seit letzes Jahr mache ich mehr: Laufen, Schwimmen, Gewichtheben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dieses Jahr, ich will ein Läufer werden. Und ich will auch mein Deutsch verbessern. 😁 Sooo hier ist mein Plan, und meine 3 Ziele für 2024:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erreichen dem Niveau B2 auf Deutsch 😱&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beenden ein Marathon 😱&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ein Sixpack zu bekommen 😂 (ich bin seriös!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year in August, &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/objectif-75-kg-et-toucher-le-sol.html"&gt;I set 2 goals for myself&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lose weight down to 75kg while losing mostly fat and trying to gain muscle (body recomposition): ✅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my flexibility and reach my toes with my fingers: ✅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I'm aiming bigger. 2 months ago, to work towards these goals, I created weekly goals for myself. After trialing them for many weeks, I've been able to identify what works for me and what's unrealistic, and correct some of them. Here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🏊 Swim 1k (just so that I don't drown in my next triathlon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🏃 Run 15k (I expect to do more every week, but I don't want to pressure myself with some high number)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🦶 &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/plantar-fasciitis.html"&gt;Fascia stretching&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jSO1-3Obt7Y"&gt;muscle strengthening&lt;/a&gt; twice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🧘 Fingers to toes twice (flexibility)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🏋️ Workout:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abs twice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pecs once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biceps + triceps once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shoulders once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🇩🇪 30 minutes of German everyday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I wrote in &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/objectif-75-kg-et-toucher-le-sol.html"&gt;my August article&lt;/a&gt; about my daily routine. This thing never really worked for me. It stuck for a month or two and then I gradually gave up, it was too demanding, 20+ minutes per day, on top of everything else. So this year I'm ditching it. Instead, I'll focus on fixing up my fascia and strengthening my muscles. I'll try to keep working on my flexibility though, but I don't want nor need it to be a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="running-milestones-for-2024"&gt;Running milestones for 2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I'll be taking part in multiple competitions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A half-marathon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://berliner-firmenlauf.de/"&gt;Berliner Firmenlauf&lt;/a&gt;: 5.5kms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://berlin-laeuft.de/s25berlin/"&gt;25 kilometers of Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small triathlon, where the running part is only 5km-long&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, to wrap up the year, a full marathon!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having these regular milestones should make this goal a little more achievable and less frightening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll try and keep this article updated as I make progress towards these goals. :) Bis nächtes Mal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I'll try to write auf Deutsch from now on too, from time to time. Emphasize on &lt;strong&gt;try&lt;/strong&gt; :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="goals"></category><category term="running"></category><category term="bike"></category></entry><entry><title>Objectif 75 kg et toucher le sol</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/objectif-75-kg-et-toucher-le-sol.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-27T18:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-08-14T12:14:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2023-08-27:/objectif-75-kg-et-toucher-le-sol.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nouveaux objectifs pour cette fin d'année 2023&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Les choses sont dites : voilà mes 2 objectifs fixés pour cette fin d'année 2023. 4 mois pour les atteindre. De nombreuses heures passées sur Youtube. Cet article en est une synthèse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je pèse actuellement un peu moins de 80 kg (j'étais à 80 il y a quelques semaines) pour 1m87 et j'ai donc pour objectif d'atteindre 75 kg de manière stable d'ici à la fin de l'année. De manière stable, c'est-à-dire idéalement dès fin Octobre, et être capable de conserver ce poids pendant les mois de Novembre et Décember sans trop d'efforts ni faire attention à ce que je mange. Pourquoi ? Pour m'améliorer à la course à pied mais surtout au vélo, et particulièrement en montagne. Aussi pour essayer de redessiner un peu ce qu'il y a devant mes abdos, mais ça c'est du bonus !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concernant ma flexibilité, mon focus sera porté sur mes jambes et notamment ma partie postérieure. Mon exercice de réference sera celui où l'on se penche en avant, en étant debout sur ses jambes tendues, en essayant de toucher le sol avec ses mains. Je pars de loin, très loin : aujourd'hui j'arrive à descendre mes mains à 22cm du sol maximum, pas plus bas. Le but est donc d'atteindre zéro d'ici à la fin de l'année. Pas forcément les mains à plat au sol, mais au moins toucher le sol du bout des doigts. Pourquoi ? Pareil, pour les performances sportives, parait-il que cela aide. Mais aussi car je me suis rendu compte que j'étais raide comme un piquet. 😁&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/flexibility.jpg" alt="Quelqu'un qui se penche vers l'avant" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Mon objectif n'est pas mettre les mains au sol, juste toucher du bout des doigts&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id="comment"&gt;Comment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pour-le-poids"&gt;Pour le poids&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sur le papier c'est plutôt simple, rééquilibrage alimentaire (adieu les chips et le pesto 3 fois par semaine), réduire un peu les quantités (pour atteindre un léger déficit calorique de 25% maximum), et augmenter légèrement le dose de sport hebdomadaire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="alimentation"&gt;Alimentation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rééquilibrer son alimentation passe par comprendre et connaitre ce que l'on mange. Pour la plupart des produits autres que fruits et légumes que l'on mange, il est écrit au dos la quantité de kilocalories et macro-nutriments (protéines/glucides/lipides). Pour perdre du poids, tout en évitant de perdre trop de masse musculaire (&lt;a href="https://www.valdemarne.fr/newsletters/sport-sante-et-preparation-physique/est-il-possible-de-perdre-du-poids-en-conservant-sa-masse-musculaire"&gt;les muscles sont des réserves d'énergie utilisées par le corps en priorité lorsque de l'on est en déficit calorique, avant d'aller chercher dans le gras&lt;/a&gt;), il est important d'augmenter son apport en protéines, et de réduire son apport en lipides au minimum vital (j'ai lu quelque part 0.8g par kilo de masse sèche par jour - quelqu'un pesant 80kg et ayant 20% de graisse, donc 64 kg sec, devra manger 64 kg * 0.8 = 51g de lipides par jour). Un bon objectif d'apport en protéines par jour peut être 1.8g/kg de masse sèche (115g par jour pour une personne de 80kg avec 20% de graisse). À savoir que l'&lt;a href="https://www.anses.fr/fr/content/les-prot%C3%A9ines"&gt;apport de base recommandé en France pour une personne est de 0.83g/kg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deux vidéos Youtube en particulier m'ont beaucoup aidé sur le sujet :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XpXr87nGIpg?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_b351LPn9XU?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La deuxième vidéo m'a permis de calculer ma consommation calorique quotidienne approximative (en prenant en compte le sport) et donc d'en déduire quels grammages viser pour chaque macro-nutriment, pour ce rééquilibrage alimentaire et ce déficit calorique d'environ 25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sur une base de 0.8g de lipides/kg sec et par jour, et 1.8g de protéines/kg sec et par jour, voici ce que je vise:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Macronutriments&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;g&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;kcal&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;% total&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Protéines&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;115&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;461&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;26%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Glucides&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;207&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;828&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;47%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lipides&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;51&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;461&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;26%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1750&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(et c'est là que je me rend compte que je mangeais de base vraiment pas assez de protéines)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensuite c'est simple, il suffit de peser, noter et compter tout ce que l'on mange, en partant de l'étiquette du produit que l'on mange, ou si l'information est manquante en allant voir sur &lt;a href="https://www.les-calories.com/"&gt;les-calories.com&lt;/a&gt;. Voilà par exemple mon dernier repas :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/kcal.png" alt="Tableau des valeurs nutritionelles de mon dernier repas" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Pas mal équilibré non ?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ici par exemple, sur l'étiquette du Quinoa il était noté que 100g contenait 351 kcal, 14.8g de protéines, 58.5g de glucides, et 5g de lipides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour finir, il est important de noter qu'en étant &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/cycling-and-being-vegetarian.html"&gt;végétarien&lt;/a&gt; il peut être difficile de réussir à ingérer autant de protéines par jour. Une manière simple et efficace pour y remédier pourra être d'utiliser des compléments alimentaires, comme la Whey, bien connue des adeptes de la musculation, trouvable dans n'importe quel Décathlon, solution pour laquelle j'ai optée.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puisque je vais augmenter mon apport en protéines, autant favoriser leur assimilation. Apporter trop de protéines d'un coup dans un repas ne sera pas bénéfique car le corps ne pourra pas tout utiliser. Il est intéressant donc de rajouter une ou deux collations par jour, 30 à 60 minutes avant le déjeuner et le diner. Si ça tombe sur une journée avec séance de musculation, la collation se fera juste après la séance. Associer à 30g de Whey un fruit, pour éviter que les protéines ne soient transformées en sucres (comme expliqué dans &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wq_qdRA0C9Q"&gt;cette vidéo&lt;/a&gt; à 7'26).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voilà d'autres vidéos sur le sujet, tout aussi intéressantes :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/wq_qdRA0C9Q?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/M4K0s792wAU?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/d8V9ZaSq9Oc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qyqJpQU8f-Y?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id="sport"&gt;Sport&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour le sport, pas dur, je faisais déjà du sport intensif en moyenne 2 à 3 fois par semaine (vélo de route + course à pied), sans compter les trajets quotidiens à vélo en ville ni mes marches à pied de 30 min quasi-quotidiennes. J'ai simplement décidé de rajouter une ou deux activités supplémentaires par semaine : soit &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/workout.html"&gt;une séance de musculation&lt;/a&gt; (30min max) du haut du corps (bras ou perctoraux, là où ça ne risque pas de nuire à ma recherche de souplesse donc), soit une session de yoga ou de mobilité/étirements. J'ai aussi rendu ma marche quotidienne non optionnelle. Ça devrait suffire...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enfin, pour suivre l'évolution de mon poids, nouvelle habitude, une pesée chaque matin après un passage aux toilettes mais avant de se réhydrater, pour avoir des conditions le plus similaires possible chaque jour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pour-la-flexibilite"&gt;Pour la flexibilité&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour ce second objectif, vu que je pars de loin, je m'attends à voir des résultats assez rapidement, avant que ma progression ne commence à ralentir. Pour travailler ma flexibilité, je vais donc miser sur :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;une session une fois par semaine de yoga (au moins 30 minutes), remplaçable par une session de mobilité et étirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;une routine quotidienne de moins de 20 minutes de mobilité et étirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bon à savoir : lorsqu'on s'étire, il ne faut jamais atteindre la douleur, au risque de se blesser, seulement atteindre une sensation d'incomfort. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dNCyC4gV_34"&gt;L'idéal est de ne pas faire durer chaque répétition plus de 30 secondes. 2, 3 ou 4 répétitions par exercice par séance d'étirement donne de bons résultats. Il faut aussi faire un mélange d'exercices statiques (sans mouvement) + passifs (sans contraction musculaire) et d'exercices dynamiques (avec mouvement) + actifs (muscle opposés solicités pour étirer).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://pilates.com.sg/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/5se_artL_active-vs-passive-stretching.jpg" alt="Image montrant les différences entre statique, passif, dynamique et actif" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Différences entre statique, passif, dynamique et actif&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pour ma routine quotidienne donc, pareil, beaucoup d'heures passées sur Youtube. La conclusion de ces recherches est la suivante :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relaxation de la nuque, 5 rotations lentes de la tête en la faisant pencher dans un sens, 5 dans l'autre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/shorts/1rVdbHYz3C0"&gt;Correction de la posture de la colonne vertébrale contre un mur&lt;/a&gt; : 10 reps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allongé sur le dos, jambes en tailleur, pieds joints, laisser les jambes tomber sur le côté sans forcer, 30 secondes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assis en tailleur, dos droit incliné vers l'avant, pieds joints tenus par les mains, on appuie légèrement graduellement sur les mollets avec les avant-bras pour ramener les genoux le plus bas possible. 2 reps, 30 secondes chacune. Version dynamique en appuyant par à-coups sur les cuisses, et non progressivement, mais lentement quand même.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allongé sur le dos, croiser la cheville droite sur la cuisse gauche. Attraper la cuisse gauche derrière le genou, la tête posée sur le sol et tirer la vers jambe vers le buste progressivement. 2 reps de 30 secondes pour chaque jambe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 minute de neurodynamique du nerf sciatique : voir &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TeqzyDnawTI&amp;amp;t=390"&gt;Comment TOUCHER SES PIEDS? ( routine COMPLÈTE expliquée )&lt;/a&gt; à partir de 6'30.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debout, se pencher en avant, les mains qui pendent vers le sol, en respirant lentement : à chaque respiration, essayer de descendre un peu plus bas et toucher les mains au sol. 2 reps, 30 secondes chacune. Cela permet d'étirer les muscles ischio-jambiers. Exercice alternatif : &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/sSdsH7F32Jo?si=yukuwAumg7e_lMhs&amp;amp;t=128"&gt;assis, une jambe tendue, l'autre pliée avec le pied contre la cuisse opposée&lt;/a&gt;. On essaie d'atteindre chaque pied en alternant les jambes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debout, un pied devant l’autre, la jambe avant fléchie et la jambe arrière tendue. Pousser le talon de la jambe arrière dans le sol, garder le buste droit (les mains sur la taille). Cet exercice peut être fait face à un mur comme support. 2 reps de 30 secondes chacune par jambe. Permet de travailler les mollets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Le classique &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rvrY8tWBT-U"&gt;étirement du psoas&lt;/a&gt;, en partant d'une position de chevalier au sol, un genoux en sol, le pied à l'arrière posé à l'envers, et en s'avançant vers l'avant, dos droit. 2 reps de 30 secondes par jambes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allongé au sol à côté d'un mur, caler les fesses contre le sol et le mur, jambes en l'air le plus droit possible contre le mur à la verticale. Plier les genoux si trop difficile. 30 secondes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optionnel, en cas de fasciite plantaire: &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/plantar-fasciitis.html"&gt;aller voir cet article&lt;/a&gt; (6 * 30 reps sur un pied (protocole de Stanish) avec du poids, en portant des altères par exemple). Idéalement il faudrait faire ces exercices plusieurs fois par jour pour vraiment accélérer la guérison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On peut rajouter en bonus si on a le temps un squat de 30 secondes, les pieds à plat si possible, le plus bas possible, les mains liées bien en avant pour faire contre poids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/I/61YIShGEJGL._AC_UF1000,1000_QL80_.jpg"&gt;La routine de Bob Anderson&lt;/a&gt; est une alternative classique à ma routine quotidienne, assez répandue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;D'autres routines que j'aime bien :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iQc4lLYljbk"&gt;Beginner stretching routine! For TikTok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eQHmKJh20_c"&gt;What stretches to do in 10 minutes. Follow along.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zNhqYaa79jY"&gt;Souplesse &amp;amp; Mobilité à Suivre en 15min ✔️ (Tout le corps sans matériel)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TeqzyDnawTI"&gt;Comment TOUCHER SES PIEDS? ( routine COMPLÈTE expliquée )&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PX1mLdKFD_w"&gt;Comment Corriger Sa Posture En 10 Minutes ! (POUR TOUJOURS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ui3ToKZtKIs"&gt;FIX Tight Hamstrings in Just 3 Steps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Une routine axée sur la course à pied : &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=80EvnW-GSHo"&gt;5' par jour d'exercices de mobilité = moins de blessures ET plus de performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Une routine qui travaille la mobilité : &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oMg6WYXb49M"&gt;DEBLOQUE ta MOBILITE en 5 minutes avec cette ROUTINE ultra COMPLETE.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Une routine pour travailler ses splits : &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0PSyHeb298g"&gt;Comment Devenir Souple TRÈS Vite ✔️ (j'ai essayé...)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour aller plus loin sur le sujet de la souplesse, quelques liens :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.3bikes.fr/2021/05/05/le-travail-de-la-mobilite-pour-etre-plus-performant-et-eviter-les-blessures/"&gt;Le travail de la mobilité pour être plus performant et éviter les blessures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aucun étirement pré activité physique (course à pied, vélo, etc), seulement des échauffements. Quant aux étirements post-exercice, ils ne sont pas forcément utiles, cela dépends des gens : &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m6fuqkM0UX4"&gt;Quand faut il s'étirer ? kiné&lt;/a&gt;. À 3'10, la vidéo parle des étirements statiques (afin de réduire des douleurs) vs exercices de mobilité dynamiques (pour gagner en amplitude de mouvement).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RDV dans 4 mois 😉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="mise-a-jour-2023-11-01"&gt;Mise à jour : 2023-11-01&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ça y est je viens de toucher le sol, il y a quelques minutes !!! Et pas qu'une fois ! Techniquement, on était encore le 31 Octobre ! Bon, de la pointe de doigts certes mais c'était mon objectif !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depuis deux mois, après une progression rapide les premiers jours, j'ai été de moins en moins assidu, au point de ne m'étirer presque plus qu'une fois par semaine. Alors il y a plusieurs jours, je me suis repris en main, étirements tous les jours, et depuis 2 jours, 3 fois par jours ! Et là, miracle, progression de ouf ! Jusqu'à aujourd'hui : après 10 minutes passées à descrendre progressivement, j'y suis arrivé, j'ai touché le sol ! Allez, on continue comme ça, objectif pour fin décembre : ne plus mettre 10 minutes à toucher le sol, mais quelques minutes, idéalement presque réussir à froid ? Ça s'annonce pas simple :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concernant le poids, le graphe parle de lui-même... 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/poids-aout-octobre-2023.png" alt="Courbe de poids" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Évolution de mon poids de fin Août à fin Octobre 2023&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintenant, on stabilise ça jusqu'à fin décembre, et on essaye de moins compter les calories !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="mise-a-jour-2024-01-13"&gt;Mise à jour : 2024-01-13&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annnd it's a wrap! Ça y est, les 4 mois sont passés. Où en suis-je ? Y suis-je parvenu ? Ai-je maintenu mes 75 kgs ? Est-ce que je touche toujours le sol avec mes doigts ? OUI et OUI ! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/poids-aout-2023-janvier-2024.png" alt="Courbe de poids" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Évolution de mon poids de fin Août à début 2024&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indéniablement, le mois de décembre aura fait quelques dégats, mais rien d'irréparable ! On continue tout ça sur 2024 maintenant ! :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="weight"></category><category term="flexibility"></category></entry><entry><title>Est-ce que je vais me faire vacciner ?</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/est-ce-que-je-vais-me-faire-vacciner.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-07-19T12:30:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-01-14T23:35:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2021-07-19:/est-ce-que-je-vais-me-faire-vacciner.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Une vidéo sur pourquoi il n'y a aucune raison de ne pas se faire vacciner&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/GBzJ77y8Bho" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.arte.tv/fr/videos/104055-000-A/covid-19-la-course-aux-vaccins/"&gt;Covid-19, la course aux vaccins (Arte)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/C_A_Gustave/status/1482036177335115779"&gt;Depuis plusieurs semaines, vous avez forcément entendu ces propos au sujet des vaccins anti-COVID : "le vaccin n’est pas parfait, sinon il nous protègerait longtemps, comme pour la grippe" ; "ce n'est pas un vrai vaccin, sinon on n'aurait pas besoin de tant de doses"...&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1482036177335115779.html"&gt;alternative link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/lionel_case/status/1409858174765654021"&gt;Pour répondre à l'argument du "il y a X% de vaccinés parmi les néo-infectés"&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1482036177335115779.html"&gt;alternative link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="covid"></category><category term="vaccine"></category><category term="pfizer"></category><category term="vaccin"></category></entry><entry><title>Living in Germany: A Doctoliber's Journey To Berlin</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/living-in-germany-a-doctolibers-journey-to-berlin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-02-13T17:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-09-24T12:11:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2020-02-13:/living-in-germany-a-doctolibers-journey-to-berlin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;About my professional relocation&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@romain.pellerin/a-doctolibers-journey-to-berlin-8e791383aa00"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;„Ich bin ein Berliner” — myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this has been true for the past two months at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before that, I lived in Paris for more than two years. It was cool: Paris is an amazing city to live in and there’s so much to see and do. Everything is constantly in motion and busy. Life is intense over there. More importantly, working for Doctolib France is truly awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But over time I grew tired of it, not being a native Parisian myself. I missed living abroad, I was seeking new challenges, I needed to get out of my comfort zone — and let’s be honest: I wanted a bigger and cheaper apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2018, Doctolib opened its second tech center, right here in Berlin. What started as a 2-person adventure back then is now a rapidly growing engineering hub with more than 40 people, including 20 software engineers (and counting).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pretty much knew when the Berlin tech center opened that I’d want to relocate at some point. I had yet to experience Berlin as a local though. so that’s what I did in March 2019. I was able to join a feature team in Berlin as a full-time member for two weeks through a Doctolib program called “&lt;em&gt;Vis Ma Vie&lt;/em&gt;” (Live My Life). This program is a great way to discover processes that different teams use and to also learn more about unfamiliar business scopes. At the end of those two weeks, I knew Berlin would be the next step in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started setting things in motion once I got back to Paris. I wanted my move to be as smooth as possible, for both my work-wise and personal life. The first step was to tell my manager about my plans. With the VPs of Engineering in France and Germany, we laid out a more concrete plan for me. We decided which team I’d join, based on my preferences and where I’d be most helpful. A few months later I was asked to choose a date for my first day in the Berlin office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time went by, it felt like things were accelerating. I first had to plan my actual move. Moving furniture and a bunch of boxes between countries is not easy. Then I needed to find a place I’d call home for at least a few weeks while settling down in Berlin. Doctolib helps with the relocation costs (flight, movers and temporary housing mostly) as well as the services of a relocating coach through &lt;a href="https://www.expath.de/"&gt;Expath.de&lt;/a&gt;. This made my whole experience much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my involvement with my French team at Doctolib began to wind down, I worked more with my future team in Berlin, remotely. My last day in the Paris office was bittersweet. I was sad to leave people I loved but excited about my new life to come! And then it happened!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/doctolib-berlin/cargo-bike.jpg" alt="Me on a cargo bike" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Me adapting to life in Berlin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, a few weeks in, I find myself looking out the window for inspiration on how to end this article. But all I see is darkness. Yes, sunset is an hour earlier than in Paris here. 😂 That’s something I’m still not used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing is certain: I’m already in love with Berlin and happy to be part of Doctolib’s adventure in Germany!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come join us! Come have fun and revolutionize health care in Europe! &lt;a href="https://careers.doctolib.de/"&gt;🇩🇪&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://careers.doctolib.fr/"&gt;🇫🇷&lt;/a&gt; Or you can also &lt;a href="http://bit.ly/doctotechlife"&gt;subscribe to our tech newsletter&lt;/a&gt;. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published on &lt;a href="https://medium.com/@romain.pellerin/a-doctolibers-journey-to-berlin-8e791383aa00"&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="berlin"></category><category term="germany"></category><category term="doctolib"></category></entry><entry><title>Living in Germany: Moving To Berlin</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/living-in-germany-moving-to-berlin.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-01-12T18:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-07-22T19:43:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2020-01-12:/living-in-germany-moving-to-berlin.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everything one has to go through when relocating to Berlin -- alternatve title: All the shit I went trough&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/FgTntxySQBY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is it folks, I am now officially a resident of Berlin, Germany! After over 2 years in Paris, it was about time for me to move. Here's to a new adventure!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But wait a second. An international move doesn't happen with a snap! In this article, I list all the tasks I had to go through to make my move as smooth and painless as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="months-in-advance"&gt;Months in advance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I recommend reaching out to &lt;a href="https://www.expath.de/"&gt;https://www.expath.de/&lt;/a&gt;, they're specialized in helping people move to Germany. I used their services. They also assign you a "coach", a person who will help you once you make it to Berlin. This person is going to help you register, find an apartment, etc. They can assist over emails too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I suggest you start selling the furniture you don't want to keep as soon as possible, as it can take days or weeks for people to buy it. If you wait too long, you'll most likely end up underselling your stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="weeks-in-advance"&gt;Weeks in advance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancel your home internet subscription&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get information about how to cancel your home insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="days-ahead"&gt;Days ahead&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancel utilities subscriptions (electricity, water)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirect/forward mail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="finding-a-short-term-flat"&gt;Finding a short-term flat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/extra/Flats_Handout 2019v5.pdf"&gt;Useful PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://wunderflats.de"&gt;https://wunderflats.de&lt;/a&gt; - registration is almost always possible, this is the website I recommend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thehomelike.com"&gt;https://www.thehomelike.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crocodilian.de"&gt;https://www.crocodilian.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.airbnb.com"&gt;https://www.airbnb.com&lt;/a&gt; - always ask beforehand if registration is possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.roomsurfer.com"&gt;https://www.roomsurfer.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.exberlinerflatrentals.com"&gt;https://www.exberlinerflatrentals.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zwischenmiete.de"&gt;https://www.zwischenmiete.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="days-after-moving"&gt;Days after moving&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="registration-anmeldung"&gt;Registration (Anmeldung)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must ask your temporary landlord to provide you with a document called &lt;em&gt;Wohnungsgeberbestätigung&lt;/em&gt;. Ideally get the original document, not a scan. This is the document you'll be bringing to the &lt;em&gt;Bürgeramt&lt;/em&gt; (police station or city hall) on the day you register, alongside your ID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure to &lt;a href="https://service.berlin.de/dienstleistung/120686/"&gt;book a slot for registration ASAP&lt;/a&gt;, as it usually takes weeks to get an appointment. Bring the following documents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registration Form filled in (can also be found at the &lt;em&gt;Bürgeramt&lt;/em&gt;): &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.berlin.de/formularserver/formular.php?402608"&gt;Anmeldung bei einer Meldebehörde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EU ID or passport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mietvertrag&lt;/em&gt; (lease)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://serviceportal.hannover-stadt.de/downloads/datei/MTIxNTstOy92YXIvd3d3L2h0bWwvaGFubm92ZXIvbWVkaWVuL2Rva3VtZW50ZS93b2hudW5nc2dlYmVyYmVzdGFldGlndW5nLnBkZg%3D%3D"&gt;Wohnungsgeberbestätigung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; filled out by landlord, or yourself if you own the place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are married or in a civil partnership, and moving together from one place to another, you can fill one registration form for two people and show up together at the same appointment. Otherwise, make 2 appoitments et one form per person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also note that you are required to notify the &lt;em&gt;Bürgeramt&lt;/em&gt; when you leave (&lt;em&gt;Abmelden&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on the topic: &lt;a href="https://www.settle-in-berlin.com/anmeldung/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.simplegermany.com/anmeldung-germany/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://allaboutberlin.com/guides/anmeldung-in-english-berlin"&gt;there&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="register-for-the-tv-tax-rundfunkbeitrag"&gt;Register for the TV tax (Rundfunkbeitrag)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rundfunkbeitrag.de/buergerinnen_und_buerger/formulare/index_ger.html"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="finding-a-long-term-flat"&gt;Finding a long-term flat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1jw-geK3X5fxCMfJMeF90eGQVAwktOvN42i5RctUnc2k/edit#heading=h.4rxwb3gjrtlm"&gt;Apartment hunting&lt;/a&gt; is no different than &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/living-in-paris-looking-for-an-apartment-in-paris.html"&gt;in Paris&lt;/a&gt;. Except that here, almost all landlords will ask for a German-specific document: your &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://mag.n26.com/how-to-get-your-schufa-score-in-germany-bb60295a7e1a"&gt;SCHUFA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (or credit score in English).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of SCHUFAS: the one with the actual credit score (called &lt;strong&gt;SCHUFA BonitätsAuskunft&lt;/strong&gt;), and the one that only states whether you have any debts or not (called &lt;strong&gt;SCHUFA Bonitätscheck&lt;/strong&gt;). In most cases, the latter is enough. You can get it for 30 euros at &lt;a href="https://www.immobilienscout24.de/"&gt;www.immobilienscout24.de&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the actual search now, here are the most used websites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.immobilienscout24.de"&gt;www.immobilienscout24.de&lt;/a&gt; - definitely the one I recommend most&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.immonet.de"&gt;www.immonet.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.immowelt.de/suche/wohnungen/mieten"&gt;www.immowelt.de/suche/wohnungen/mieten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://salzundbrot.com/"&gt;salzundbrot.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ebay-kleinanzeigen.de/s-wohnung-mieten/c203"&gt;www.ebay-kleinanzeigen.de/s-wohnung-mieten/c203&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wohnungsboerse.net/"&gt;www.wohnungsboerse.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.lieblingsmieter.de/"&gt;www.lieblingsmieter.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware of scams on these websites, as you would do in any other country. When it's too good to be true, it's most likely a scam. Also, you should never send any private document before going to a viewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, go to viewings prepared. Bring a file with the following documents:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A nice introduction about you with a picture. Make sure to state if you own pets, if you have children, whether you smoke or not and if you play music. Explain why you're looking for an apartment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mieterselbstauskunft&lt;/em&gt;: find a template online and pre-fill it. Most landlords provide their own versions: in such a case, use theirs and fill it in while doing the viewing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passport/ID scans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scan of your Anmeldung&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scan of SCHUFA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy of work contract (&lt;em&gt;Arbeitsvertrag&lt;/em&gt;): only include relevant pages (first and last pages usually, as well as the page that says your salary -- make sure to highlight it in yellow!!! -- also if you're not on a probationary period make sure to include the page stating that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last three payslips (&lt;em&gt;Gehaltsabrechnungen&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proof of timely payments to your previous landlord (&lt;em&gt;Mietschuldenfreiheitsbescheinigung&lt;/em&gt;). A letter from them will do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also be asked to send these documents digitally after the viewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vivreaberlin.com/trouver-un-logement.html"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; you'll find additional advice about the apartment search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="weeks-after-moving"&gt;Weeks after moving&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bank-account"&gt;Bank account&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider &lt;a href="https://allaboutberlin.com/guides/first-bank-account-in-germany"&gt;opening a German bank account&lt;/a&gt;, you might need it to get paid for example. The easiest solution remains N26 though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="various-insurances"&gt;Various insurances&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://allaboutberlin.com/guides/insurance"&gt;Germans are known to like insurances&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.expatica.com/de/finance/insurance/insurance-in-germany-100952/"&gt;so much that many various ones exist&lt;/a&gt;. Only a few are required by law though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://allaboutberlin.com/guides/german-health-insurance"&gt;Health insurance&lt;/a&gt;: I was told to stick with public insurance (as opposed to private) and go with &lt;a href="https://www.tk.de/en"&gt;TK&lt;/a&gt; as they are big and English-friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work insurances: you get them automatically as soon as you start working, no need to worry here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vehicule insurance: if you own a car only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other optional insurances but highly recommended are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liability insurance (called &lt;em&gt;Haftpflichtversicherung&lt;/em&gt;): &lt;a href="https://www.settle-in-berlin.com/personal-liability-insurance-germany/"&gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://allaboutberlin.com/guides/haftpflichtversicherung"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In a nutshell, the 3 ones I saw and heard about repeatedly that are English-friendly and managed through an app are: GetSafe, Coya and PopSure. You can compare others &lt;a href="https://www.check24.de/privathaftpflicht"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Axa is apparently big and has a reputation in Germany. Same for Allianz. Anyway, a decent price is around 50 euros a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Household contents insurance (called &lt;em&gt;Hausratversicherung&lt;/em&gt;): only if you have valuable items or piece of furniture at home. It also covers bikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="misc"&gt;Misc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.settle-in-berlin.com/bike-in-berlin/"&gt;Get a bike&lt;/a&gt; and read &lt;a href="https://bikeinberlin.com/"&gt;BikeInBerlin.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.berlin.de/land/kalender/?+c=63"&gt;Register your bike&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="https://adfc-berlin.de/service/43-codierung.html"&gt;other link here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.visitberlin.de/en/blog/top-11-berlin-flea-markets"&gt;Go to flea markets&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://bikeinberlin.com/index.php/2018/02/11/berlin-bike-flea-markets/"&gt;bike flea markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://marlonbernardes.github.io/awesome-berlin/en/pages/public-transport.html#how-to-buy-transport-tickets"&gt;Get a monthly or yearly public transport ticket&lt;/a&gt;. Good to know: with a monthly (and surely a yearly one) subscription, you can bring a friend along on the weekend and on weekdays after 8pm for free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.settle-in-berlin.com/"&gt;Read settle-in-berlin.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moving? Instead of renting a truck, &lt;a href="https://bikeinberlin.com/index.php/2018/03/11/die-flotte-free-cargo-bikes-rent-berlin/"&gt;rent a cargo bike&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://flotte-berlin.de"&gt;for free&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="more-on-germany"&gt;More on Germany&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thelocal.de/20200121/the-german-habits-internationals-say-they-cant-shake-off"&gt;The German habits internationals say they can't shake off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thelocal.de/20200120/5-key-things-you-need-to-know-about-the-german-workplace"&gt;5 key things you need to know about German working culture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://marlonbernardes.github.io/awesome-berlin/"&gt;Awesome Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.simplegermany.com/"&gt;Simple Germany&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W-nDCrIk5yM"&gt;33 Awesome Things To Do in Berlin in Winter - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="berlin"></category><category term="germany"></category><category term="apartment"></category><category term="housing"></category></entry><entry><title>The Way I Work</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/the-way-i-work.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-02-17T23:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-02-18T12:37:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2019-02-17:/the-way-i-work.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My daily routine to focus and remain productive&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I stumbled upon &lt;a href="http://blog.samaltman.com/productivity"&gt;this article on productivity&lt;/a&gt;. I found it very inspiring. It somehow convinced me to rethink the way I work. Since then, I've been actively working on perfecting my daily workflow to be more productive and also more organized. Reducing my stress level was also one of my goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think having a clearly defined and established workflow is more important than most people think. I find habits to be comforting. They help me concentrate and focus on what matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advice given in this article doesn't apply to everybody. Being a software engineer has its own constraints and requirements. In this article, I speak about work environment, tools and fighting physical and mental fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="todotxt"&gt;TODO.txt&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the most important task one has to do daily is defining a list of priorities for the day to come. It is very important to know what to work on and when.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried for a long time to keep a TODO list on a piece of paper (or in a booknote). It was working, but not as well as I wished. The main problem was that I needed to be physically present at my desk to access my list or edit it. That's why I eventually switched to a digital TODO list. Many people resort to apps for that, Evernote being one of the most popular I believe.  I however use a simple text file. I find these note taking apps too distracting, with countless features I would never use. What I like about my text file is the simplicity of it. Plus I can access it at any time, as long as I am carrying my work laptop. Plus I am not tempted to access it outside of office hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading and editing my TODO list is something I do many times throughout the day, as I need to re-arrange my priorities and when I get work done. Moreover, at the end of each day, I make sure to prepare my TODO list for the following day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My TODO list is a simple plain text file yet it has its own sections, separated by empty lines. The topmost lines of the file are the tasks I need to get done by the end of the day, sorted from the most urgent one to the least. Then, the second section contains tasks that must be worked on in the short term, preferably in the month to come. Finally comes the third section which is a backlog of tasks I want to work on some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been putting all this into practice for a few months now and I must admit it's working well for me. No distractions, simplicity, I can add/edit/remove entries with a few keystrokes, I can also make backups or send it over emails in seconds. In short, I love it. A stress-free TODO list, always up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is an extract of my list, in its current state:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Finish feature 1691
- Book plane tickets and hotel for Berlin trip

- Delete 2 `const workshopVisitMotivesCountScenario = workshopVisitMotivesScenario(motives)` in `onChange`?
- Schedule meeting front guild early April
- Move Jenkins loc() to Heroku

- Articles ideas
  - eslint
  - code/bundle splitting
  - download/parse/exec time
  - debugging with devtools (CSS, ...) in ffox and chrome (breaking point with mouse clicks, ...)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id="bookmarks"&gt;Bookmarks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bookmarks are an essential feature of any web browser. However, not everyone agrees on how to use it. Even I use bookmarks differently on my personal laptop than on my professional laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professionally, I use bookmarks for websites I rarely visit, so rarely that neither me or my browser can remember the URL. What I mean by the browser can't remember it is that it does not show up in the list of suggested URLs are I type in the URL bar. I sort my bookmarks by topic, in folders named according to their topic. A few examples of folders I have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;COMPANY-RELATED&lt;/em&gt;: payrolls, holidays, expensify, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;TO READ LATER&lt;/em&gt;: lengthy articles I'll probably read some day while waiting for the CI tests to run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;REACT TRAININGS I GIVE&lt;/em&gt;: Asana list to keep track of the sessions, useful links to share&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1-ON-1&lt;/em&gt;: contains stuff related to my quaterly objectives, the list of engineering roles and associated levels in my company, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;TO PRESENT&lt;/em&gt;: things I want to present at the next All Hands meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never bookmark websites I visit daily, or frequently. Why? Because I can at least remember some part of the URL, or the title, and my browser is smart enough to autocomplete it and suggest it automatically. For websites I visit many times a day, like the Pull Requests page on Github, or my Twitter feed, I create keyboard shortcuts to access them instantly. For instance, Github Pull Requests is &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;Super&amp;gt;+G&lt;/code&gt; (G as in Github).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I used to have bookmarks for every website. It wasn't until recently when I switched to very few bookmarks that I noticed how stressful it was for me to have all these bookmarks being constantly displayed before my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="opening-new-pull-requests"&gt;Opening new Pull Requests&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Github, I've got some interesting things to say about Pull Requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically open a new Pull Request every time I start working on a new feature, a new bug fix, or when I'm refactoring code. When the specs are not great, it's sometimes hard to know precisely what needs to be done, code-wise. How do I deal with this? First, I start working on what is obvious: be it the core feature, or creating a new empty React component, creating a new Rails controller, etc. Then I git commit, push and open the Pull Request. That first commit is usally quite small in terms of changes. Only then do I start listing what is "left to be done" in the Pull Request description. Github offers a convenient way to create TODO lists in markdown, with actual checkboxes that are checkable. Just write "&lt;code&gt;- [ ] Something to do&lt;/code&gt;" and it'll be displayed as a list item prefixed with an unchecked checkbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the TODO list is ready, I add the "WIP" label as well as my team label, and resume working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="inbox-and-thunderbird"&gt;Inbox and Thunderbird&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any email people receive fall in one of these three categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Action required on your side: it could be a quick action (like replying) or a time-consuming one (like filling a form)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporal information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important information that must be kept for a long time, or files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works essentially just like a mailbox. Mail people get in their mailboxes also fall into these categories: bills are actions required on your side, postcards are temporal information, payrolls are important information, parcels are like files, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody would open a mailbox, see what's inside, and leave it there. Therefore, it does not make any sense to have inboxes full of emails. I am doing Inbox Zero: I aim (and almost always succeed) at keeping my inbox empty. My strategy is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I open my email client a few times a day, usually at the beginning of the day, before lunch, after lunch, a few times in the afternoon when I'm on code-breaks, and before leaving work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I process emails one by one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it's an "action required" email and the action takes less than 5 minutes, I do it immediately then delete the email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it's an "action required" email and the action takes more than 5 minutes, I keep the email in my inbox and add a new entry in my TODO list such as "&lt;em&gt;reply to email from X&lt;/em&gt;" or "&lt;em&gt;do what X asked for&lt;/em&gt;". I will then delete the email when the action is done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it's a temporal information, I take note of it if needed and delete the email immediately. A temporal information could be a Google Calendar invite, a JIRA edit from my colleagues, an incident reported by New Relic, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it's an important information, I move the email into the appropriate subfolder (they're called labels in Gmail). An important information could be a contract (PDF document), an organizational change, a POST-MORTEM document that I believe will be useful in the future, a train ticket that will eventually be deleted when the trip is done, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I just said, I use Gmail labels quite a lot, in the sense that many emails end up in labels. However, I only have a handful of them. Here are a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trips: business trips (train tickets, hotels, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Front stack: any important email regarding frontend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archives: anything that does not belong to another category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rely on Gmail filters extensively. I get a lot of emails I don't need to see at all, that I want deleted automatically. For instance, I often check the notifications on Github, therefore I don't need to also see the emails they send me. Also, our staging environment is deployed with every new commit (every 10 minutes or so), therefore I don't need to know every time a new commit is deployed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I must confess I use Thundebird, and not the Gmail website. And I'm proud of it. The reasons I use Thunderbird are listed below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It works offline: I can access my emails when not connected to the Internet. Even though it happens very rarely, it's very handy when in the train for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gmail is a website, and not a lightweight one. The tab consumes a lot of RAM memory, and opening/closing/opening the websites several times a day is not a better alternative, as it takes many seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gmail is distracting: there's Google Hangout in the left bottom corner, many buttons here and there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don't like the conversation-grouping feature of Gmail, I never got used to it. Thunderbird also has it but I disabled it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thunderbird is simple, RAM-efficient. And having a distinct program for emails help see it as something important, it's not just another tab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="slack-and-distractions"&gt;Slack and distractions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/slack.html"&gt;I hate Slack&lt;/a&gt;. But I have to deal with it. Slack is distracting (notifications mostly), there's a lot of noise and not much information. There are two-people conversations involving everyone, there are company-wide conversations to which only two people are contributing. There's the fear of missing out, and the useless necessity to read all the unread messages when coming back from days off. Plus important messages and notices get often lost in the never-ending flow of messages. It becomes hard to differentiate what's important from what is not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my strategy here is very simple: I open Slack every time I open Thunderbird. Sometimes, I leave it open for longer periods of time, when I'm actively engaged in a conversation. But overall, I try to use it as little as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="open-spaces-headphone-and-sound"&gt;Open spaces, headphone and sound&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/open-offices.html"&gt;I also hate open spaces&lt;/a&gt;. Everyone is forced to share everyone else's emotions. Everyone is an indirect contributor who did not volonteer to someone else's conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem with open spaces is sound, or most specifically noise. People talking out loud, laughing, going to the bathrooms, etc. I'm fighting this with a headphone. I wear it almost all the time, most of the time with no music playing. It acts as a symbolic barrier, it helps my brain isolate itself and focus. When I am actually listening to music, it has to be either a song I've heard a thousand times, so that I'm already used to it, or some lyricless song. It helps me get in the zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="standing-up"&gt;Standing up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving on to the physical section now... I've been using &lt;a href="http://www.thefreedesk.com/"&gt;a standing desk&lt;/a&gt; for a year now, at work. And I am entirely satisfied. I alternate between sitting and standing throughout the day, sometimes several times. &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/a-sedentary-life.html"&gt;It has many advantages&lt;/a&gt;. I am feeling more energetic overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="sports"&gt;Sports&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently started going to the gym many times a week. I am lucky enough to have a gym in the very same building, where I work. My sessions are usually split in two: first I do 15 minutes of jogging, then 30 minutes of workout. In a matter of weeks, I have noticed so much improvement on my sleep quality and productivity during the day. Short nights don't have a toll on me anymore, like they used to. Not that it's advisable or that I like it, but when it happens I can easily handle a few short nights in a row now. Not to mention the slight weight loss. I usually go 2 or 3 times a week, after work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is it. That's how I work. I hope you found something useful, or maybe you've learned something? I think most people don't pay enought attention to their daily routine and workflow. They don't seek improvement and don't see the importance of being healthy. There are many ways to reduce stress while increasing productivity. It could be a tiny habit to change or a big one. I think everyone should reflect on that every once in a while, and try to improve the way they work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="work"></category></entry><entry><title>Favorite Movies</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/favorite-movies.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-10T00:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T02:03:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2017-02-10:/favorite-movies.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My all time favorite movies. Or some of them.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just like I started listing &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/books.html"&gt;the books I read&lt;/a&gt;, I want to list some of my favorite movies. So here is a first attempt to list them. Of course, I probably forgot lots of them, so I'll keep updating this article occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the moment, the list is unordered. I'll certainly re-order that at some point, when it gets confusing and messy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La La Land: &lt;em&gt;great actors, excellent OST&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whiplash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Birdman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin Again: &lt;em&gt;great OST&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dead Poets Society&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good Will Hunting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forrest Gump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seven Pouds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Titanic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avatar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Wars movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue Valentine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive: &lt;em&gt;great OST&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Shawshank Redemption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hannibal movies with Hopkins (chronological order for the story): Hannibal Rising, Red Dragon, The Silence of the Lambs, and Hannibal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pursuit of Happyness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I Am Legend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Rocky movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ex Machina&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leon The Professional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside Lewyin Davis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juno&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get Out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limitless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your name (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grave of the Fireflies (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisper of the heart (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My neighbor Totoro (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wind Rises (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wolf Children (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Girl Who Leapt Through Time (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kiki's Delivery Service (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Marnie Was There (Japanese anime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Catch Me If You Can&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creed movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top Gun movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harry Potter movies 1 to 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blade Runner and Blade Runner 2049&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Django Unchained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cast Away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Notebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Artist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matrix movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;San Junipero (an episode from the TV series &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hang the DJ (an episode from the TV series &lt;em&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="movies"></category></entry><entry><title>My Travel List</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/my-travel-list.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-31T16:55:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-09-23T00:04:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2017-01-31:/my-travel-list.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Places I want to visit.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1 id="usa"&gt;USA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dallas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redwood State Park&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huston&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Miami&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Texas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mount Rushmore National Memorial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Philadelphia (especially the Rocky Statue and the Rocky Steps)&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forrest Gump Point in Utah (GPS coordinates: 37.1015063,-109.9908129)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boston:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Museum of Fine Arts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="japan"&gt;Japan&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chureito Pagoda, Kyoto (I've been there, but never climbed the stairs to get the wonderful view of Mount Fuji - Chureito Pagoda)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Miyajima (Itsukushima)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanazawa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="china"&gt;China&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great Wall of China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beijing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shanghai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lijiang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yu Garden, Shanghai&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="europe"&gt;Europe&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vienna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hallstatt, Austria &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Prague&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greece&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cyprus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Berlin, Hamburg and Munich, Germany&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scandinavia: Denmark, Sweden, Norway (Geirangerfjord)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Finland&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Italy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Rome&lt;/del&gt; and Venice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colosseum in Verona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Tower of Pisa&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;Madrid&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="other-countries"&gt;Other countries&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iceland (I want to see Northern lights so bad!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eldhraun, Iceland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greenland or Northern Canada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machu Picchu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chichen Itza (Mexico)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mexico City&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marrakech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rio de janeiro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Zealand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moscow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saint Petersburg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phuket and Patong, Thailand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vietnam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turkey:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pamukkale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anıtkabir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malaysia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Philippines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taiwan (Taipei and Kaohsiung)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senegal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Australia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pura Ulun Danu Bratan, Indonesia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rijeka Crnojevica, Montenegro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Petra, Jordan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="travel"></category></entry><entry><title>Books</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/books.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-26T16:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-05-26T13:46:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2017-01-26:/books.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Books I have read&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1 id="june-2012-july-2019"&gt;June 2012 - July 2019&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Walking Dead&lt;/strong&gt; (comic books), &lt;em&gt;by Robert Kirkman&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Charlie Adlard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="2016"&gt;2016&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The New Digital Age: Reshaping the Future of People, Nations and Business&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Eric Schmidt and Jared Cohen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elon Musk: How the Billionaire CEO of SpaceX and Tesla is Shaping our Future&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Ashlee Vance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1984&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by George Orwell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal War One&lt;/strong&gt; (all volumes), by &lt;em&gt;Denis Bajram&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal War Two&lt;/strong&gt; (volumes 1 &amp;amp; 2), by &lt;em&gt;Denis Bajram&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zombies&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Zombies Néchronologies&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Sophian Cholet&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Simon Champelovier&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Olivier Peru&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="2017"&gt;2017&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animal Farm&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by George Orwell&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal War Two&lt;/strong&gt; (volume 3), by &lt;em&gt;Denis Bajram&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Day&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;David Nicholls&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here's Negan&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Robert Kirkman&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Charlie Adlard&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Love Is Love&lt;/strong&gt;, comic &lt;em&gt;published by DW Publishing, in collaboration with DC Entertainment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="2018"&gt;2018&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shangri-la&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Mathieu Bablet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;La Belle Mort&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Mathieu Bablet&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Descender&lt;/strong&gt; (comic books), by &lt;em&gt;Jeff Lemire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dustin Nguyen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delivering Happiness: A Path to Profits, Passion, and Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Tony Hsieh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orcs et Gobelins 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/strong&gt; (comic books), &lt;em&gt;by Jean-Luc Istin, Diogo Saïto, Sylvain Cordurié &amp;amp; Giovanni Lorusso&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;La Horde du Contrevent 1&lt;/strong&gt; (comic book), &lt;em&gt;by Éric Henninot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And a few "first issue" comic books, including Outcast, Riverdale, The Wicked + The Divine, Infinite Dark, Blackbird&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="comics-i-started-reading-that-year"&gt;Comics I started reading that year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper Girls&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Brian K. Vaughan&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Cliff Chiang&lt;/em&gt;, ended in 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Rick Remender and Greg Tocchini&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Die!Die!Die!&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Robert Kirkman&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Scott M. Gimple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saga&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Brian K. Vaughan&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Fiona Staples&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="2019"&gt;2019&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lean Startup&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Eric Ries&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Le code du cycliste&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Ludovic Duprey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guide des aménagements cyclables&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Paris en Selle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stoner&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;John Edward Williams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="comics-i-started-reading-that-year_1"&gt;Comics I started reading that year&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ascender&lt;/strong&gt; (comic books), by &lt;em&gt;Jeff Lemire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dustin Nguyen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="20232024"&gt;2023/2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyperion&lt;/strong&gt;, by &lt;em&gt;Dan Simmon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="2024"&gt;2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Culture Map&lt;/strong&gt;, by Erin Meyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="to-read"&gt;To read&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.numerama.com/pop-culture/531136-7-romans-de-science-fiction-deprimants-et-geniaux-a-lire-avant-la-fin-du-monde.html"&gt;7 romans de science-fiction déprimants et géniaux à lire avant la fin du monde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goodbye, Things: The New Japanese Minimalism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Winners Take All: The Elite Charade of Changing the World&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It Doesn't Have to Be Crazy at Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;World War Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck: A Counterintuitive Approach to Living a Good Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Les misérables Tome V - Jean Valjean (French Edition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Les Misérables: Tome IV (Volume 4) (French Edition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Les Miserables: Tome III - MARIUS (French Edition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Les misérables: Tome 2 Cosette (Volume 2) (French Edition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Les Misérables: Tome 1 : Fantine (French Edition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Germinal (French Edition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Together Is Better: A Little Book of Inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the Shortness of Life: Life Is Long if You Know How to Use It (Penguin Great Ideas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Clean Coder: A Code of Conduct for Professional Programmers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean Code: A Handbook of Agile Software Craftsmanship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;McGraw-Hill's Conversational American English: The Illustrated Guide to Everyday Expressions of American English (McGraw-Hill ESL References)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Sound Really Clever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the French Think: An Affectionate Portrait of an Intellectual People&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2001: a Space Odyssey (Space Odyssey Series)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Astronaut's Guide to Life on Earth: What Going to Space Taught Me About Ingenuity, Determination, and Being Prepared for Anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work Rules!: Insights from Inside Google That Will Transform How You Live and Lead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="books"></category><category term="comics"></category></entry><entry><title>My RSS Subscriptions</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/my-rss-subscriptions.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-18T23:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-29T16:32:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2016-12-18:/my-rss-subscriptions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The RSS feeds I subscribed to.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of all the websites I subscribed to. Those are very interesting and cover a wide variety of topics. A few of them are in French though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="bike"&gt;Bike&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pausevelo.com/feed/"&gt;Pause Velo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cyclocast.fr/category/Podcast/feed/"&gt;Podcast – Cyclocast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cause-commune.fm/podcastfilter/rayons-libres/feed/"&gt;rayons libres – Cause Commune – Paris – 93.1 FM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="computers"&gt;Computers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/2ality?format=xml"&gt;2ality feed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.mozfr.org/feed/atom"&gt;Communauté Mozilla francophone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://infrequently.org/feed/"&gt;Infrequently Noted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://hacks.mozilla.org/feed/"&gt;Mozilla Hacks – the Web developer blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://overreacted.io/rss.xml"&gt;Overreacted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.cavelab.dev/index.xml"&gt;blog.cavelab.dev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="germany"&gt;Germany&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://feeds.thelocal.com/rss/de"&gt;The Local&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tip-berlin.de/english/feed/"&gt;tip english – tipBerlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="humor"&gt;Humor&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.commitstrip.com/fr/feed/"&gt;CommitStrip&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.commitstrip.com/en/feed/"&gt;English feed&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLS9S-RWXlfOfL8I4LC54_AWqU-IWgsngH"&gt;LE MOMENT MEURICE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/feeds/videos.xml?playlist_id=PLtScWTSuZmZUcSpgFBy9eWH7-ZAljq6iE"&gt;L'ABC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.monkeyuser.com/feed.xml"&gt;MonkeyUser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="rss"></category><category term="feed"></category></entry><entry><title>Fixing My Life</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/fixing-my-life.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-05T19:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-10-01T03:08:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2016-11-05:/fixing-my-life.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How I fixed my life&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have spent the last few months trying to "fix my life". To put it differently, I tried to identify what was wrong and how I could improve my life in general. Although in good shape and healthy, I wanted to be more energetic. Likewise, I had a few bad habits that I wanted to get rid of. Let's go through them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="health"&gt;Health&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quit smoking&lt;/strong&gt;: that was definitely the hardest. In total, I'd say it took me several months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercice at least 30mins per day&lt;/strong&gt;: not always doable. At KAIST, I am fortunate enough to have a gym right next to my dorm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eat healthy food in moderate quantities (not too much, not too little)&lt;/strong&gt;: not easily doable at KAIST. Ultimately, I'd like to become &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KriTQ0aTrtw"&gt;a vegetarian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop using electronic devices at least 1 hour before going to sleep&lt;/strong&gt;: this is important in order to sleep well. Screens are known to prevent you from falling asleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every hour of sitting, stand up for a few minutes&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://www.everythingsouthcity.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Sitting-page-001.jpg"&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="culture"&gt;Culture&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read books (novels) in English&lt;/strong&gt;: I am reading "Animal Farm" at the time being.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep learning English on a regular basis&lt;/strong&gt;: the book "The Elements of Style" is on my nightstand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write in English&lt;/strong&gt;: that's what I do with this blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="lifestyle"&gt;Lifestyle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owning as few things as possible. Ideally my whole life would fit in two suitcases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_INOPfPdhB4"&gt;Anti-consumerism&lt;/a&gt;. It is a mindset I adopted a while ago.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="other"&gt;Other&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check Twitter two times a day tops&lt;/strong&gt;: that one is pretty hard, I am still struggling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to bed before 2am&lt;/strong&gt;: same. At some point in the future, being a morning person?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I also started learning about topics that are not related to my skills whatsoever, such as politics, the environment, green energies, etc. I would recommend these videos as a good starting point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=90CkXVF-Q8M"&gt;Before the Flood&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Join Leonardo DiCaprio as he explores the topic of climate change, and discovers what must be done today to prevent catastrophic disruption of life on our planet.&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZoGH7d51bvc"&gt;Réformons l'élection présidentielle (FR)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.demain-lefilm.com/en/film"&gt;Demain&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Climate is changing. Instead of showing all the worst that can happen, this documentary focuses on the people suggesting solutions and their actions.&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I recently found that &lt;a href="http://www.inc.com/marcel-schwantes/a-23-minute-morning-ritual-that-will-transform-your-whole-day.html"&gt;interesting article&lt;/a&gt; which suggests "&lt;em&gt;A 23-Minute Morning Ritual That Will Transform Your Whole Day&lt;/em&gt;". I am still working on it... Essentially, it gives 5 things to do in the morning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down three acts of gratitude (2 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journal one positive experience you've had during the past 24 hours (2 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditation (2 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Express kindness through a text or email (2 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, here are my &lt;strong&gt;New Year's Resolutions for 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play another musical instrument&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Dutch and Spanish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to dance Rock and Roll or salsa or swing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="further-reading"&gt;Further reading&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.bradfieldcs.com/in-2017-learn-every-language-59b11f68eee"&gt;In 2017, learn every language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mobile.nytimes.com/2016/12/31/opinion/sunday/how-to-become-a-superager.html"&gt;How to Become a ‘Superager’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/feb/11/smartphone-technology-addiction-facebook-twitter"&gt;How I quit my smartphone addiction and really started living&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="update-2023-10-01"&gt;UPDATE: 2023-10-01&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was just randomly scrolling through past articles on my blog when I stumbled upon this one. I thought this deserved an update, 6 years later! Let's go through all the bullet points I had listed back then and try to see what happened with each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quit smoking&lt;/strong&gt;: I must admit this was kind of a lie. When I wrote this I was in South Korea. I had greatly reduced how much I smoked but I would not say I had completely stopped. I remember smoking a couple of times in nightclubs there. Also, the following year (2017), I started smoking again while in San Francisco. I remember my own deception after so many months without smoking. Anyways. My very last cigarette drag was in July or August 2019. Since then, not a single one. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exercice at least 30mins per day&lt;/strong&gt;: if my 30-minute times two bike commute and my daily walks in the park nearby count towards it, then I definitely hit that! If not, then I'm very close, and my weekly exercise time is way above 4 hours anyways, thanks to regular long bike rides on the weekend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eat healthy food in moderate quantities (not too much, not too little)&lt;/strong&gt;: hell yeah, this has become second nature since &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/cycling-and-being-vegetarian.html"&gt;a couple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/objectif-75-kg-et-toucher-le-sol.html"&gt;of months now&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully it'll stick long time. Back in 2016 I mentioned that I wanted to become vegetarian ultimately... This happened end of 2018 and I am still vegetarian to this day. No reason to change that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop using electronic devices at least 1 hour before going to sleep&lt;/strong&gt;: that one never worked. On my phone till the very last minute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every hour of sitting, stand up for a few minutes&lt;/strong&gt;: whenever I'm in the office, yeah I totally do that. At home it depends on how focused on some task I am, but I mostly do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read books (novels) in English&lt;/strong&gt;: huge hiatus from the end of 2019 until 2 months ago, when I started reading Hyperion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep learning English on a regular basis&lt;/strong&gt;: not at all. I guess my current level is more than enough. On the flipside, I'm considering learning German further and aim for the B2 level (my current level is A2/B1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write in English&lt;/strong&gt;: every single day, at work, texting friends, on this blog, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owning as few things as possible. Ideally my whole life would fit in two suitcases&lt;/strong&gt;: the 2 suitcases thingy... yeahhhh no. Can't happen. Won't happen. But I'm still trying to only own stuff than I truly need. Like I never buy clothes or shoes, I think I already have enough for the next 10 years. Not that I have so many, but who needs more than 3 pairs of jeans, or 20 t-shirts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anti-consumerism&lt;/strong&gt;: yup, still valid, that's me. Only buy what you need. I favor second hand as much as possible, except for things I know I will keep for life or whose lifespan isn't so long.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check Twitter two times a day tops&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/twitter-we-are-breaking-up.html"&gt;I broke up with Twitter 🎉&lt;/a&gt;. Now I'm struggling with Youtube. I spend way too much time watching random shit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to bed before 2am&lt;/strong&gt;: am I ever gonna learn?! Overall there has been improvement. I'm usually in bed before 1am, now targeting midnight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's check out my &lt;strong&gt;New Year's Resolutions for 2017&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more: failed, at best I maintained the same level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play another musical instrument: major failure. I did buy a ukulele in 2018 though 😂&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Dutch and Spanish: not even tried. Did I mention German? 😅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to dance Rock and Roll or salsa or swing: some day, some day...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ha ha that was funny, looking back at the old me from 2016 and my life goals. What would I add today? Probably more stretching, more weight lifting, at least more frequently. Going to bed earlier, rising earlier? And more German of course! Meet me here in a few years for an update. 😉&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>My Dream Laptop</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/my-dream-laptop.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-11-04T01:50:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-30T22:42:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2016-11-04:/my-dream-laptop.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The specs of my dream laptop&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am writing this here for posterity. All suggestions are welcome. I will definitely update this article as my requirements change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="must-have"&gt;Must have&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screen&lt;/strong&gt;: 14 to 15"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CPU&lt;/strong&gt;: Intel i5 or i7 (6th or 7th generation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RAM&lt;/strong&gt;: 8GB or more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSD&lt;/strong&gt;: 256GB or more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ports&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USB-C port&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 at least&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video port&lt;/strong&gt;: 1 at least (HDMI preferably)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debian-compatible&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Battery&lt;/strong&gt;: must last for 5 hours at least&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A webcam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Headphone jack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lightweight&lt;/strong&gt;: less than 2.5kg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="optional-but-appreciated"&gt;Optional but appreciated&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charging over USB-C port&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="not-required-i-dont-mind-having-these-features-or-not"&gt;Not required (I don't mind having these features or not)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Touch screen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CD/DVD drive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="i-dont-want"&gt;I DON'T WANT&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A numeric keypad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A MacBook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="laptops-i-considered-buying-at-some-point-in-2017"&gt;Laptops I considered buying at some point in 2017...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dell 7480&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dell XPS 15 (although the screen is 15.6")&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lenovo ThinkPad T470&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turned out I bought the Dell 7480.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="links"&gt;Links&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/broken-window/my-search-for-a-macbook-pro-alternative-e549ea2b2dee"&gt;My search for a MacBook Pro alternative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://stallman.org/intel.html"&gt;Reasons not to use Intel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-word-on-lenovo"&gt;A word on Lenovo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/todayininfosec/status/1023059171220979715"&gt;2013: Intelligence sources disclosed that...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2013/7/30/4570780/lenovo-reportedly-banned-by-mi6-cia-over-chinese-hacking-fears"&gt;Lenovo reportedly banned by MI6, CIA, and other spy agencies over fear of Chinese hacking (update)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.geek.com/chips/spy-agencies-shun-lenovo-finding-backdoors-built-into-the-hardware-1563801/"&gt;Spy agencies shun Lenovo, finding backdoors built into the hardware (Updated)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="computer"></category><category term="laptop"></category></entry><entry><title>The TV series I watch</title><link href="//romainpellerin.eu/the-tv-series-i-watch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-06-02T01:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-30T19:50:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Romain Pellerin</name></author><id>tag:romainpellerin.eu,2015-06-02:/the-tv-series-i-watch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some of the best TV series in the last decade&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The past decade offered us a bunch of high-quality TV series. Here are my favorite ones (not sorted).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="shows-still-running"&gt;Shows still running&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lupin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tribes of Europa&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formula 1: Drive to Survive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squid Game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tales of the Walking Dead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tour de France: Unchained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Walking Dead: Dead City&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Walking Dead: Daryl Dixon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="ended-or-canceled-tv-series"&gt;Ended or Canceled TV series&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Walking Dead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear The Walking Dead&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Walking Dead: World Beyond&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Walking Dead: The Ones Who Live&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper Girls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ted Lasso&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;La Casa de Papel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Altered Carbon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vikings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breaking Bad + El Camino (a Breaking Bad movie ) + Better Call Saul&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Halt and Catch Fire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun Records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="tv-shows-i-dropped"&gt;TV shows I dropped&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 100 (after season 2 or 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sense 8 (after the very sexual episode, a Christmas special)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legion (after season 2, episode 7)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Westworld (after season 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Narcos (I watched season 1 and 2 for sure - 3 I am not so sure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="About me"></category><category term="televion"></category><category term="tv series"></category></entry></feed>