<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Romain Pellerin's Blog - Sports</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 01:14:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>Running: Building My Own Training Plan</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/running-building-my-own-training-plan.html</link><description>&lt;h1 id="goal"&gt;Goal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W-13 until my first marathon ever. Time to start an actual training plan. Since the beginning of 2024, I was using the app &lt;a href="https://www.campus.coach/"&gt;Campus Coach&lt;/a&gt; for that. It's pretty good but far from perfect. It's also subscription-based, 15 euros per month (they do have a freemium version but it's too limited). They ask you many questions to customize the plan they build but after it's been created, I found it not flexible enough. For instance, it's not possible to postpone a session. Also, one cannot set a goal finish time for a race, instead the app will give an estimated finish time and adjust it over time as progress is made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, it was not perfect, so I decided to look for an alternative. And I found &lt;a href="https://www.decathlon-pacer.com/"&gt;Kiprun Pacer&lt;/a&gt;, from Decathlon. Pretty different approach, it lets you drive your training more, and the sessions suggested are quite different. For instance, one can set their goal finish time. Also, it's free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I thought I'd fully explore and use these 2 apps to the fullest one after the other, for 2 races, hence 2 training plans and compare them. Ultimately as I do so, my goal is to understand how plans are created, what to adjust to make them truly personalized, so that I can build my own plans in the future, without any app, paid or free. I want my plans to be flexibile, I want them to adjust to my week schedule changes, not the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll start with Kiprun Pacer until October, and then from January until April 2025 I'll be using Campus Coach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="aug-oct-2024-kiprun-pacer"&gt;Aug-Oct 2024: Kiprun Pacer&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up my plan with the following parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I intend to do 4 sessions per week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The race is on October 27th, 2024. It sets the plan duration to 13 weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not want to skip the evaluation phase&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goal finish time: 3h29'00"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Campus Coach, the app also asks you for your personal records, to fine tune the training even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what it's worth, I just completed today my &lt;a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitesse_maximale_a%C3%A9robie"&gt;MAS test&lt;/a&gt; and the result is: 16.95 km/h! It's commonly said that a marathon is usually run between 75% and 80% of one's MAS. 75% of 16.95 km/h = 12.71 km/h. In othr words, a pace of 4'44"/km, or a finish time around 3h19". So my goal of 3h29'00" for a first marathon sounds realistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pros"&gt;Pros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app plans each week, i.e. it assigns a fixed day for each session, as opposed to simply telling you to do the sessions in the week the way you want. I need that sort of thing, otherwise I tend to poorly schedule my runs throughout a week. To do that, the app first asks you how many days a week you want to train, and which ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sessions can be postponed/rescheduled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app lets you set a goal finish time before you start any plan, and will adjust all the sessions towards that goal, love it 😍&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After a run, if you have connected your Garmin account to it, the app detects that the run was one from your training plan, and automatically "ticks it off". It then asks you a couple of optional questions, like "did you take pleasure in the run?", "how hard was it?", etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the weeks in one's training plan are categorized. For my 13-week plan, those weeks fell in the following categories, in this order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evalutation (MAS (Maximal Aerobic Speed) test) week - 1 week&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ramping up - 4 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific pace - 5 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharpening - 3 weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cons"&gt;Cons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The sharpening (i.e taper) phase of my 13-week plan was &lt;strong&gt;a bit long and way too brutal&lt;/strong&gt;. The decrease in kilometers is too big and too sudden. Week 10: 77.48 kms. Week 11: 42.09 kms. Week 12: 36.19 kms. Week 13 (race week): 15.13 kms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="jan-mar-2025-campus-coach-paid-version"&gt;Jan-Mar 2025: Campus Coach (paid version)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="pros_1"&gt;Pros&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a dedicated section in the app where to see your progress over time, and your expected progress to come. That's very motivating!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="cons_1"&gt;Cons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The app does not let you set a goal finish time at the beginning of a plan. Instead it gives you an estimated time, and adjusts it as you make progress. The runs at specific pace are set to the ideal pace for you according to the app, not your goal pace. That sucks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After a run, even if the app is connected to your Garmin account, you have to manually "validate the session", i.e. match your run in Garmin with a session in your plan in the app. A couple of more clicks, avoidable. Then it asks questions, like the Kiprun app, only less.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="conclusion-how-training-plans-are-built"&gt;Conclusion: how training plans are built&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, here are some bullet points on my learnings on how to build training plans yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one trains 4 times a week, then most weeks should look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One easy jog, wihout speeding up at all, to build up one's endurance (&lt;em&gt;endurance fondamentale&lt;/em&gt; in French)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One run specifically targetting the marathon pace (a.k.a. specific pace), with long stretches at the pace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One quality session, with fast segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the ramp up phase, these segments are meant to be run faster than the targeted marathon pace, aimed at improving one's MAS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later in the training plan, during the specific pace phase (as one gets closer to race day), those segments will be longer but run slower, at marathon pace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One long jog, usually on Sunday, with some bits at the targeted marathon pace. At the beginning of a training plan, 1 hour or so, at the end of a plan, around 2 hours, maximum 2 and a half (a good rule of thumb is, two third of the targeted race duration).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One week out of 4 or 5 should be a recovery week, where the number of kilometers run is reduced, but also the number of fast segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The taper (a.k.a. sharpening phase) should be 2 to 3 week long for a marathon but gradual and not sudden. The peak in terms of weekly kilometers should happen the 4th week before the race, so just before the taper begins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The percent of "quality kms" in a plan (kilometers run at a fast pace) should not exceed 25% on any week (otherwise, greater risk of fatigue and injury)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nolio.io/"&gt;Nolio, a website to build your training plans or collaborate with a coach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZDdZ3TqJkd8"&gt;Decathlon Pacer: Une appli quasi parfaite avec un GROS défaut 😢&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0hQsqivvRaI"&gt;CAMPUS coach : pourquoi je ne suis pas convaincu...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I3KcGSAfw0Q"&gt;J'ai acheté 3 plans marathon à 3 coachs différents (et c'est pas fou 😓)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://www.running-addict.fr/category/plans-dentrainement/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://www.runnek.fr/blog/construire-plan-entrainement-efficace-course-pied/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://www.conseils-courseapied.com/entrainement/planification.html&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://lacliniqueducoureur.com/coureurs/programmes-de-course-a-pied/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://www.running-addict.fr/conseil-running/plan-entrainement-course-a-pied/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2024-08-03:/running-building-my-own-training-plan.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>running</category><category>training</category></item><item><title>Triathlon: Checklist</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/triathlon-checklist.html</link><description>&lt;h1 id="overall"&gt;Overall&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trisuit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sport socks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smartwatch (charged!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A transponder, worn at the ankle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A belt to carry gels and display the bib number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="for-swimming"&gt;For swimming&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swimming cap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swimming goggles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wetsuit (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="for-the-transition-swim-bike"&gt;For the transition swim -&amp;gt; bike&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small towel, to dry your feet and remove the dust/dirt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="for-cycling"&gt;For cycling&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Race bike (make it lightweight! remove unnecessary equipment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike computer (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helmet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glasses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bike shoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Water bottles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="for-running"&gt;For running&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running shoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A cap (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2024-06-02:/triathlon-checklist.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>triathlon</category><category>swim</category><category>bike</category><category>running</category></item><item><title>The Ultimate Sports Video</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/the-ultimate-sports-video.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm on a mission. A quest. A quest to make great sports videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watch Youtube a lot. Too much. Loads of ski and bike videos. And very often, I stumble upon videos which leave me speechless. Well edited, nice shots, action-oriented, upbeat music, you name it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, it was these three:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IgXoOQlyiso?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A3WtqSJ1ww0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qgMqrFiPI_g?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought I'd just start collecting ideas about what makes a great video great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="ski-videos"&gt;Ski videos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here my conclusion is that it all depends on the music. I would recommend to pick the music before starting any editing. I find songs of alternating fast phases and slow phases the best, as you can sort of tell a story. When the rythm is fast and energetic, you can cram in as much action as you want. When it's more relaxed, it's easy to switch to contemplative scenes, landscapes, etc. Here is &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@AlexGrohlMusic"&gt;a music creator on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;, who makes great background music for sports-oriented videos. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@EuphoriaAudioMusic"&gt;Here's another channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the shots now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid shooting in shadow, prefer under sunrays. Likewise, avoid cloudy weather. Foggy weather on the flip side can be nice for a change, for one or two scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Target people, ideally one person, instead of a group, when skiing. A group is fine on a chairlift, or when everyone has come to a stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid filming people's back. Prefer skiiing by their side (close to them, or at a distance), or ahead of them. It's better to see people's faces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the time, film people closely. I find shots where the suject is getting closer and then farther away pretty cool, when there's movement. Likewise, overtaking someone at high speed (or being overtaken) makes really nice shots. But if you're to maintain the same distance, remain close as much as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast-paced skiing scenes are better than slow ones :) except if the subject ends up falling 😁&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't forget to record landscapes, mountains, sunsets, etc. Film while being on a chairlift. These scenes are nice for moments when the music slows down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shoot when the sun is out and at sunset/sunrise, when it's very low in the sky. Alternating between different times of the day helps tell a story in a video. For instance, sunsets are nice to end a video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record at 50FPS at times, when the scene has potential to be slowed down. When editing the video, consider speeding up some landscape shots too (or shots of crowds, cities, etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carving shots make an impression! For these shots, it's fine to film a subject from behind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="cycling-videos"&gt;Cycling videos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I have not given these types of videos much thought. I'll make sure to come back here and update this article when I do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and by the way... Here's my latest attempt at making a cool video 😎:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/N0WoxVaDKcQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 23:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2024-02-14:/the-ultimate-sports-video.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>ski</category><category>bike</category><category>video</category></item><item><title>Workout</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/workout.html</link><description>&lt;h1 id="how-many-reps"&gt;How many reps?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, to build muscle, one should reach muscle failure after 6 to 12 reps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="How many reps to build strength/muscle/endurance" src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/workout-reps.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Source: &lt;a href="https://www.missionpossiblefitness.com.au/blog/44-method-behind-the-madness-prescribing-rep-ranges/"&gt;https://www.missionpossiblefitness.com.au/blog/44-method-behind-the-madness-prescribing-rep-ranges/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on the topic in these videos (in French), from 5'30 on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UgoItZgNuAM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from 4' on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8U6mHtWTs6Y" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id="how-many-sets"&gt;How many sets?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mensjournal.com/health-fitness/rep-range-builds-most-muscle"&gt;3-6 sets seems to be recommended quite often for hypertrophy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-much-rest-time-between-sets"&gt;How much rest time between sets?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to find reliable data, and it seems there is no consensus. But for hypertrophy, &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19691365/"&gt;30-60 seconds&lt;/a&gt; is often cited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="other-resources-and-videos"&gt;Other resources and videos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/BkS1-El_WlE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/m2LfqLLjWE4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QsYre__-aro" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XM8-SyMFrRc" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the last minute of the video above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="./videos/abs-routine.webm" type="video/webm"&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;figure class="center"&gt;&lt;img alt="The 8-min abs workout steps from the video above" src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/abs-workout.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/extra/WORKOUT.pdf"&gt;My very own workout plan, from 2016, back when I was in South Korea.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 16:50:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2019-07-06:/workout.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>workout</category></item></channel></rss>