<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Romain Pellerin's Blog - Sports</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 23:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Ultimate Sports Video</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/the-ultimate-sports-video.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I'm on a mission. A quest. A quest to make great sports videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watch Youtube a lot. Too much. Loads of ski and bike videos. And very often, I stumble upon videos which leave me speechless. Well edited, nice shots, action-oriented, upbeat music, you name it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, it was these three:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IgXoOQlyiso?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/A3WtqSJ1ww0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/qgMqrFiPI_g?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought I'd just start collecting ideas about what makes a great video, great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="ski-videos"&gt;Ski videos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here my conclusion is that it all depends on the music. I would recommend to pick the music before starting any editing. I find songs of alternating fast phases and slow phases the best, as you can sort of tell a story. When the rythm is fast and energetic, you can cram in as much action as you want. When it's more relaxed, it's easy to switch to contemplative scenes, landscapes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the shots now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid shooting in shadow, prefer under sunrays. Likewise, avoid cloudy weather. Foggy weather on the flip side can be nice for a change, for one or two scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Target people, ideally one person, instead of a group, when skiing. A group is fine on a chairlift, or when everyone has come to a stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid filming people's back. Prefer skiiing by their side (close to them, or at a distance), or ahead of them. It's better to see people's faces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the time, film people closely. I find shots where the suject is getting closer and then farther away pretty cool, when there's movement. Likewise, overtaking someone at high speed (or being overtaken) makes really nice shots. But if you're to maintain the same distance, remain close as much as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast-paced skiing scenes are better than slow ones :) except if the subject ends up falling 😁&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't forget to record landscapes, mountains, sunsets, etc. Film while being on a chairlift. These scenes are nice for moments when the music slows down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shoot when the sun is out and at sunset/sunrise, when it's very low in the sky. Alternating between different times of the day helps tell a story in a video. For instance, sunsets are nice to end a video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record at 50FPS at times, when the scene has potential to be slowed down. When editing the video, consider speeding up some landscape shots too (or shots of crowds, cities, etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carving shots make an impression! For these shots, it's fine to film a subject from behind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id="cycling-videos"&gt;Cycling videos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I have not given these types of videos much thought. I'll make sure to come back here and update this article when I do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and by the way... Here's my latest attempt at making a cool video 😎:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/N0WoxVaDKcQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 23:30:00 +0100</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2024-02-14:/the-ultimate-sports-video.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>ski</category><category>bike</category><category>video</category></item><item><title>Running and Pronation</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/running-and-pronation.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So I've been a """runner""" for quite some time now and I'm just discovering what pronation is. Apparently most people are pronated, some are supinated, and very few are normal (or neutral). I fall in the first category/neutral, based on the study of the wear of my shoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being pronated means that, while standing (not moving), one's foot naturally leans inward (towards the other leg). Being supinated is the opposite, one's foot leans outward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also means that pronated runners tend to have the outmost part of their feet land slightly first when running, then feet roll progressively towards the inside (towards the other leg) until the full body weight is on one foot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two videos to help you figure out which category you fall in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1eBUsNk1ya4" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UPlss00XR-8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days I'm looking into buying a new pair of shoes. Apparently, Asics' Gel-Kayano model is a popular one among pronated runners, supposedly their top pair of shoes. I'll update this article with some feedback about them if I end up buying them...&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2023-10-01:/running-and-pronation.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>running</category><category>pronation</category></item><item><title>Plantar Fasciitis</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/plantar-fasciitis.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Alright alright alright. April the 3rd, 2022, I ran my first official half-marathon, in Berlin. Oh boy was it tough! But I did it. 2 hours and 22 seconds, official time. Not bad, although I must admit I was aiming under 2 hours. But let's blame Strava, as it was giving me the finish line 500 meters shorter. Ha ha!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/half-marathon-2022.jpg" alt="Photo of me running" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Me, about to cross the finish line&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, a race wouldn't be a race without a propre injury, would it? Well, let's be honest, it's not that bad of an injury, but still. I got... "Plantar fasciitis" (in French: &lt;em&gt;aponévrosite plantaire&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;fasciapathie plantaire&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;fasciite plantaire&lt;/em&gt;)! To be fair, it started a week prior to the race. I overtrained (I guess). Indeed, I ran 17 kilometers exactly one week before. The next day the pain came. Not too strong, but strong enough for me to call it a discomfort. I ran the race nonethless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/plantar-fasciitis/symptoms-causes/syc-20354846"&gt;random Google search&lt;/a&gt; tells me that it's&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"[...] one of the most common causes of heel pain. It involves inflammation of a thick band of tissue that runs across the bottom of each foot and connects the heel bone to the toes (plantar fascia)."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy enough, I can understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the article describes it, you feel the pain mostly in the morning near the heel, right out of bed, and after a few minutes of walking, it starts to fade away, and eventually vanishes, until the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of all the websites that I read (not many in all fairness), the best and easiest treatment is to go easy on exercising for at least a few weeks. I am currently at the end of my first "week off", I'll keep monitoring my pain and see how long it takes to completely heal. I only cycle these days, no more running until the pain is gone. I don't want it to become a chronic pain. Stretching a few times per day is also advised. Wearing a splint at night to hold the whole thing might also be considered. As to me, I'll keep resting for the time being and see how it goes. 🤞&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a simple exercice to do at home to help the healing process: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dQmn1sP70PI&amp;amp;t=55"&gt;Exercice maison pour guérir la Fasciite plantaire / Aponévrosite plantaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional French online resources about it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/4pNBatSoBKU?rel=0&amp;amp;start=218" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t8Zg-iy5Uck"&gt;La FASCIITE PLANTAIRE, finissons-en ! - EXPLICATIONS ET TRAITEMENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0mhGsu3icLg"&gt;Aponévrosite Plantaire (fasciite plantaire) : traitement kiné et exercices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=agLuZLFzcqg&amp;amp;t=500"&gt;Comment j'ai traité RAPIDEMENT mon APONÉVROSITE plantaire ?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LB_Bw5K2QKA"&gt;Je devine TON Histoire en regardant tes PIEDS ( fasciite plantaire / épine calcanéenne/pieds plat)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=G1e3TTKQDIQ"&gt;Visite chez le physio : ou en est ma douleur au pied ?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S52UVKkDI5w"&gt;COMMENT TRAITER L'APONÉVROSITE PLANTAIRE ?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://podformance.com/fasciite-plantaire-chronique-6-mois-et-plus-differents-traitements-a-envisager/"&gt;Fasciite plantaire chronique (6 mois et plus) – Différents traitements à envisager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QuVv1IGD1Hc"&gt;3 exercices pour soulager l'aponévrosite plantaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aJt6U5kMaJ4"&gt;Massage de l'aponévrose plantaire - Fasciite plantaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DnmRzukeUJI"&gt;Comment soigner l'aponévrosite plantaire ? Running et Sport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZFXEbn-66Sc"&gt;SOIGNE 🥰 ta TENDINITE d’Achille et ton APONEVROSITE plantaire 😱grâce à ces EXERCICES de KINE.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="update-2023-03-31"&gt;UPDATE: 2023-03-31&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dang it's been a year!!! So many things happened! First of all, I ran again more than 10 kms for the first time since the half-marathon... 2 days ago 😅. Why? you ask. I'm glad you asked! That thing took forever to heal... more than 9 months. I think last Christmas I could still feel it from time to time. So what happened? July or August last year, I went to the doctor, cause I was still feeling the pain EVERY MORNING. She confirmed my own diagnosis, I have a plantar fasciitis. Good news, in a way. She advises rest (of course), insoles and physiotherapie. Perfect, let's do this! 6 sessions of physiotherapie later, no changes (or very slight but not because of the therapy). The physiotherapist clearly was not seeing many patients with that sort of injury, she did her best to come up with creative exercises but I am pretty sure that did little. Next, insoles. To be honest, I'm not sure how much this helped. I got them in August or September, I would have assumed that if they worked, I should have seen a rapid improvement - that did not happen. Like I said, until Christmas I was feeling moderate/litte plain quite often. Anyway, during that whole year I basically stopped running, or 3 or 4 kms once or twice... lol. Then, since January this yearb, I pretty much never felt the pain again, at least never in the morning. Every once in a while I would feel some tickling in the foot randomly, just as a reminder that something had happened, but no pain per se, and that would only last a few seconds when walking. And now, as I'm writing these lines, I can't remember the last time I felt any kind of pain in this foot because of this injury! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this because you're injured, you're not alone 💪. Give it some time, go easy on running, maybe get insoles, use a massage ball if you have one, do some calf and foot stretching in a staircase, while standing on the edge of a step when facing the stairs (slowly let your heels drop down, repeat a few times). That should do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="update-2023-04-02"&gt;UPDATE: 2023-04-02&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just ran 22 kms today!!! 🎉 No pain, felt great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="update-2023-10-01"&gt;UPDATE: 2023-10-01&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since April, quite a lot happened. First of all, soon after running these 22 kms, I took up running again more consisently. Over the following few weeks, my foot became sore again at times. For very short amounts of time, occasionally, and rarely in the heel but rather random places &lt;strong&gt;in&lt;/strong&gt; the foot. Mild short pain. I've been monitoring this closely. Nothing unbearable at all. It just happens randomly throughout the day, seating or walking, and does not last. On a scale from 0 to 10, it's usually around 2. Let's see how this goes... I just started muscle strengthening in an attempt to fix this for good.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2022-04-26:/plantar-fasciitis.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>plantar fasciitis</category><category>health</category><category>running</category></item><item><title>Shin Splints</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/shin-splints.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;So now that I am a pro runner because I managed to run &lt;a href="https://www.strava.com/activities/5368040239"&gt;a half marathon once in my life&lt;/a&gt;, let me tell you about shin splints. Cause yeah, I got that following that run, and I could barely walk over the next 10 days, let alone running. So yes, I am kidding, I am no pro runner at all, quite the opposite actually...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="what-the-heck-is-shin-splints"&gt;What the heck is "shin splints"?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://orthoinfo.aaos.org/en/diseases--conditions/shin-splints/"&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; says it's "&lt;em&gt;an inflammation of the muscles, tendons, and bone tissue around your tibia&lt;/em&gt;". Basically, a pain around the tibia. It can be as benign as an inflammation, and be as bad as a stress fracture. Fortunately, I had the former form of it (I guess?!). It mostly happens when you're over-exercising (like running twice the distance you had previously run the longest before, on a whim), are under-prepared, when you exercice too often or don't give your body time to rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-did-i-heal"&gt;How did I heal?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I had a minor form of it (again, I guess, not sure, I did not see any doctor for that), healing took rather little time. From the day I ran till the day I was not feeling any pain any longer, 10 days went by. The pain started to kick in in the last couple of kilometers, during the run. Then, the first three days I swear I could not walk, I was limping. Oddly enough, casual urban cycling was fine. I am not talking about proper road cycling, but you know, going from A to B in a city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After these 3 first days, some googling and a lot of Youtube searching, I applied ice on my tibia 1 or 2 times a day, for a few days. In addition to that, I lightly wrapped (strapped) my leg in a gym plastic band several hours a day, something similar to a resistance band, so as to keep my flesh tight. Not too much of course, I did not want to block the blood flow. Also I did no running and very little walking on these days. The first two or three days I did not notice any improvement, and then all of a sudden, the pain when walking greatly decreased. It took another 2 or 3 days plus some proper good paced road cycling towards the end of the recovery period, for the pain to finally completely go away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am writing here is no medical advise at all, I am just sharing my personal experience. Maybe what I did was good, maybe not, maybe I would have healed faster or slower should I have done things differenlty differently, I have no clue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as I am writing this, I still have not tried running again, as I injured myself only 20 days ago, but the pain is 100% gone and I walk normaly again. Hopefully the next time I try running I'll be fine... and hopefully you'll find this article helpful. :)&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2021-06-13:/shin-splints.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>shin splints</category><category>health</category><category>running</category></item><item><title>Workout</title><link>//romainpellerin.eu/workout.html</link><description>&lt;h1 id="how-many-reps"&gt;How many reps?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, to build muscle, one should reach muscle failure after 6 to 12 reps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class="center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="How many reps to build strength/muscle/endurance" src="//romainpellerin.eu/images/workout-reps.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Source: &lt;a href="https://www.missionpossiblefitness.com.au/blog/44-method-behind-the-madness-prescribing-rep-ranges/"&gt;https://www.missionpossiblefitness.com.au/blog/44-method-behind-the-madness-prescribing-rep-ranges/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More on the topic in these videos (in French), from 5'30 on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/UgoItZgNuAM" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from 4' on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/8U6mHtWTs6Y" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id="how-many-sets"&gt;How many sets?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mensjournal.com/health-fitness/rep-range-builds-most-muscle"&gt;3-6 sets seems to be recommended quite often for hypertrophy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="how-much-rest-time-between-sets"&gt;How much rest time between sets?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to find reliable data, and it seems there is no consensus. But for hypertrophy, &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19691365/"&gt;30-60 seconds&lt;/a&gt; is often cited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="other-resources-and-videos"&gt;Other resources and videos&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/BkS1-El_WlE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/m2LfqLLjWE4" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/QsYre__-aro" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width="700" height="394" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XM8-SyMFrRc" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the last minute of the video above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls&gt;
  &lt;source src="./videos/abs-routine.webm" type="video/webm"&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="//romainpellerin.eu/extra/WORKOUT.pdf"&gt;My very own workout plan, from 2016, back when I was in South Korea.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Romain Pellerin</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 16:50:00 +0200</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:romainpellerin.eu,2019-07-06:/workout.html</guid><category>Sports</category><category>workout</category></item></channel></rss>